geopoliticalfutures.com 2018-03-09

# Privacy Policy - Geopolitical Futures

**Privacy Policy**

Introduction

Geopolitical Futures, LLC (“GPF”) reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time at its sole discretion and without sending notice to you, so you should review this Privacy Policy periodically. The effective date of this notice and any revised or changed notice may be found on this page, on the bottom left hand corner of the notice.

Privacy; Confidential Information

GPFs’ policy is to protect the confidentiality of the individually identifiable information that you provide. GPF collects the following information from you if you subscribe to our free weekly newsletter: name and email address; or subscribe to our paid website: name, e-mail address, street address, city, state, ZIP, country, phone number. In addition, if you choose to complete certain forms or send us requests, you will be asked to provide the following information: street address, city, state ZIP, phone number. Because payment is handled through a third-party payment processor, GPF will NOT see your credit card number or banking information.

You consent to GPF sharing its mailing list with our marketing partner Mauldin Economics, who may contact you directly.

GPF’s policy is to prohibit the unlawful disclosure of your personal information. To learn more about how GPF protects your personal information, please contact us at [support@geopoliticalfutures.com](mailto:support@geopoliticalfutures.com).

Mailing List for free weekly newsletter

GPF encourages all users of this Site to register for the mailing list, so that you can receive our free weekly newsletter written by George Friedman. You may unsubscribe at any time by clicking unsubscribe in the email you received when you subscribed, clicking the unsubscribe link in any content email you receive, emailing [support@geopoliticalfutures.com](mailto:support@geopoliticalfutures.com), or calling Customer Support – Toll Free:1-888-982-8217, International Callers:1-512-687-3444.

Computer Information

GPF logs your current Internet address (this is usually a temporary address assigned by your Internet service provider when you log in), the type of operating system you are using, and the type of browser software used. In addition, GPF may keep track of what portions of this Site you are visiting. GPF aggregates this information to help GPF improve or create a better experience for users of the Site. For example: GPF may upgrade those parts of the Site that are heavily visited.

Our website automatically records website usage information that we analyze statistically to track operational problems, to prevent fraud and to improve the effectiveness, security and integrity of the site. We do not use this information to track or record information about individuals. We will disclose this information to third parties only in aggregate form or as may be required by law. For each page that you visit, we collect and store the following technical information in what is called a web server log file:

Date and time of access

URL address of the GPF webpage visited

Internet domain and IP address from which our website was accessed

Type of browser and operating system used to access our site (if provided by the browser)

URL address of the referring page (if provided by the browser)

Completion or success status of the request for a web page or other on-line item

File size of the webpage visited

For the purpose of enabling better website design and a better user experience, we employ Google Analytics (a web service by Google, Inc.) to track site traffic and provide aggregate reports of how the public interacts with our website. Session cookies are employed by Google Analytics in the form of client-side JavaScript code. In utilizing this analytics service, GPF maintains its existing standards in regards to the sharing and disclosure of information, security and privacy safeguards for the data, and the data retention policy, each described below. Google Analytics analyzes website usage information automatically upon visits to the GPF website(s). Users who do not wish to have their visit information collected by Google Analytics may opt-out by downloading a browser extension or by disabling cookies in their browser settings. Opting-out of web measurements will still permit users to access the full GPF website, with all included information and functionality.

Cookies

A cookie is a piece of information that a web site sends to your computer, which is stored in a file on your computer’s hard drive. A cookie does not tell us your individual identity unless you have chosen to provide it to us. Most cookies expire after a defined period of time.

Personally Identifiable Information

The preceding paragraphs describe the categories of personally identifiable information that GPF collects in this Site for paid subscribers. If you wish to review or change the personal information you provided, please click on the “My Account” button at the top of this page.

In addition to disclosing the mailing list to GPF’s marketing partner Mauldin Economics, LLC, GPF may disclose personally identifiable information you provide to third parties if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (a) complete the sales transaction; (b) comply with legal process; (c) enforce the Agreement; (d) respond to claims that any information you provide violates the rights of third parties; (e) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of GPF, its users and/or the public; or (f) in relation to the sale, assignment, transfer or acquisition of all or substantially all of GPF’s assets or shares by a third party. Except as provided in the preceding sentence, GPF will NOT otherwise sell or trade your personally identifiable information with third parties, such as sellers of goods or services.

Tracking and Remarketing

GPF will not respond to Web browser “do not track” signals. If you would like additional information about online tracking and various opt-out mechanisms, please see http://donottrack.us/

Because we link to social media sites, and from time to time may include third-party advertisements, other parties may collect your personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across different web sites when you visit this Site.

In addition, we use Google AdWords, so we are advertising the Site online through a form of tracking called remarketing, Third-party vendors, including Google, show our ads on various sites across the Internet, and use cookies to serve you ads based on your past visits to this Site. You can opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting Google’s Ads Settings https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin . Alternatively, you can opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page. http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/

Please note that not all tracking will stop even if you delete cookies.

Encryption

GPF uses no encryption (data scrambling) on certain portions of the Site, but uses encryption on portions where you are transmitting financial information, such as credit card information. When you are on any web site that asks you for confidential information, you should check to see if the information being transmitted is encrypted in order to increase the security of your information. Keep in mind that there is no such thing as perfect security.

Children and Minors.

GPF makes no active effort to collect personal information from children under the age of 18 and does not wish to receive any such information.

Additional Rights:

Applicable laws may give you additional rights that are not described in this online privacy policy.

For further information on Privacy matters contact

General Manager, Geopolitical Futures at [contact@geopoliticalfutures.com](mailto:contact@geopoliticalfutures.com).

Effective Date: 10/01/2015

Your California Privacy Rights

California Residents:

You can deliver your requests for information on the names and addresses of the third parties to whom your name and e-mail address was provided for their direct marketing purposes, by writing to us at [contact@geopoliticalfutures.com](mailto:contact@geopoliticalfutures.com)

Please note that California limits your requests to one per year.
